<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Analyses on kama sona</title>
    <link>https://sonapona.github.io/sonapona-site/analyses/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Analyses on kama sona</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    
	<atom:link href="https://sonapona.github.io/sonapona-site/analyses/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>terminology</title>
      <link>https://sonapona.github.io/sonapona-site/analyses/terminology/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sonapona.github.io/sonapona-site/analyses/terminology/</guid>
      <description>Vocabulary Alignment Punic Staying to the official pu material.
Lapic Introducing new words for comedic purposes.
Saweic Introducing new words for the purpose of introducing new words.
Palic Introducing new words due to referring to the concepts frequently enough that conversation would be improved by having new words.
Pinic Avoiding vocabulary from after pu.
a alignment a-initial Preferring to put a at the start of phrases for emphasis:
 a pona mute!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>dialect overview</title>
      <link>https://sonapona.github.io/sonapona-site/analyses/overview/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sonapona.github.io/sonapona-site/analyses/overview/</guid>
      <description>Pinian from pini + ian
Catchall for pre-pu dialects of toki pona.
Vikenian from vk + ian
Dialect of toki pona characterised notably by:
 Tendency to compound la instead of using multiple sentences Tendency to use a initially rather than finally  Punian from pu + ian
Standard pu toki pona.
Maponian from ma pona + ian
Dialect of toki pona characterised by:
 Tendency to use nimi sin, most common being:  tonsi (queer) linwuli (connection) epiku (epic)   Standardised grammar that&amp;rsquo;s somewhat consistent among members Fast adoption of sona nasa deemed pona  Mankanian from manka + ian</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>maponian dialect</title>
      <link>https://sonapona.github.io/sonapona-site/analyses/maponian/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sonapona.github.io/sonapona-site/analyses/maponian/</guid>
      <description>Information    metric info     Speaker Count ~1k   Vocabulary Alignment Lapic-Palic   Commonly Found In Discord   A-Alignment A-Final   Complexity Alignment Pelac    Overview Maponian is one of the larger dialects of toki pona. Maponian is largely characterised by two things:
  Maponian is mostly taught through #pana-sona by a somewhat homogeneous speaker base that generally doesn&amp;rsquo;t have conflicts when trying to communicate through toki pona, resulting in a fairly standardised dialect of toki pona that incubates new speakers fast.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>mankanian dialect</title>
      <link>https://sonapona.github.io/sonapona-site/analyses/mankanian/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sonapona.github.io/sonapona-site/analyses/mankanian/</guid>
      <description>Information    metric info     Speaker Count ~100   Vocabulary Alignment Palic   Commonly Found In Minecraft   A-Alignment A-Final   Complexity Alignment Pelac    Notable Non-pu Vocabulary ewe stone, gravel, rock, pebble, lava, magma
When ewe is used, kiwen is reduced to usage for only metal.
Shared Meanings This is not a dictionary, only analysing commonly shared concepts a Mankanian speaker is likely to recognise as a primary meaning of a phrase.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>